Guide to the Liberty Hall collection, 1971-2016 MS 658
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Liberty Hall collection
1971-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Liberty Hall (Houston, Tex.)
MS 658
9.5 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
6.89 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0658aip_001 (6.89 GB)
17.2 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0658aip_003 (17.2 GB)
2.60 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0658aip_002 (2.60 GB)
This collection mainly consists of memorabilia and ephemera from the music venue Liberty Hall.
Biographical / Historical
Liberty Hall was a music venue located in downtown Houston, Texas from 1971 to 1978. It was originally owned and operated by Michael Condray, Lynda Herrera, and Ryan Trimble. Hosting a wide variety of performers, including Bruce Springsteen, ZZ Top, The Velvet Underground, The Ramones, Lightnin' Hopkins, Big Mama Thornton, and many more, it was known for its low admittance prices of sometimes only two dollars for nationally known entertainers.
Before Liberty Hall, Condray and George Banks, the future graphic illustrator of Liberty Hall posters, opened Jubilee Hall which became the Family Hand, a restaurant and entertainment venue. The restaurant was known for its red beans and rice, prepared by Thera Neumann, the African-American female chef. When Condray began looking for a new location to open with Herrera and Trimble, Neumann found the building that would become Liberty Hall. The building was originally a church built in the 1940s and later became the American Legion Post 391. On March 4, 1971, it opened as Liberty Hall.
Besides the many musicians that performed at Liberty Hall, the venue hosted plays and comedy performances. Cheech and Chong performed for a completely sold out four-night stand for two dollars a ticket. Cheech and Chong credit Liberty Hall for their success. Liberty Hall also hosted rock opera director C. C. Courtney's play "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" from March 23 to April 22, 1972. At the time, it was the longest running play in the history of Houston.
In 1974, Herrera left Liberty Hall with Condray following in 1975. Trimble stayed on until the venue closed in 1978. The building that was once Liberty Hall was soon demolished after its closing. Today, a parking lot near the Toyota Center sits where Liberty Hall once was.
Text borrowed from the "Liberty Hall (Houston, Texas)" Wikipedia page written by Woodson staff member Claire Weddle.
Content Description
This collection consists of the photographs, news clippings, posters, realia and a scrapbook documenting the history of the music venue Liberty Hall. Materials from co-owner Michael Condray's later music venture Showbar is also included.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Gerry Ebel, Lynda Herrera, Ryan Trimble, and Bruce Bryant on behalf of Richard "Ace" Brooks in 2016.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Music; Theater; Blues (Music); Rock concerts; Folk music; Folk-rock music; Rock music; Stand-up comedy; Theatrical productions; African Americans; Politics and government
Subjects (Persons)
Herrera, Lynda; Condray, Michael; Trimble, Ryan
Subjects (Corporations)
Liberty Hall (Houston, Tex.)
- Series I: General
  - News clippings from scrapbook, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Press book, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Southern Voice", 1974-04-25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Flier, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Photographs and scrapbook
  - Loose items from scrapbook, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Liberty Hall photographs, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Showbar negatives, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Showbar photographs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mike Condray Memorial images, 2016
    Scope and Contents
    The items in this file consist of images taken at Mike Condray's Memorial at Ovations Club by a Woodson staff member. These are jpg files.
- Series III: Audio and Video
  - Bruce Springsteen at Liberty Hall (2 CDs), 1974-03-09 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bruce Springsteen in KLOL Studios, 1974-03-09
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Soundcheck: Satin Doll - Beer Barrel Polka"; "Satin Doll"; "Does This Bus Stop at 82nd Street?"; "Growin' Up"; "Mary Queen of Arkansas"; "Wild Billy's Circus Story"; "Sentimental Journey"; "The Fever"; "Something You Got - Heat Wave"; Springsteen interview recorded the day before the band's appearance at the station. Bruce Springsteen - guitar, lead vocals; Danny Federici - accordian; Clarence Clemons - saxophone; Garry Tallent - tuba
  - Loudon Wainwright III live, 1973-11-09
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Down Drinking at the Bar"; "I Am the Way (New York Town)"; "Have You Ever Been to Pittsburgh?"; "New Paint"; "Nocturnal Stumblebutt"; "Bell Bottom Pants"; "Clockwork Chartreuse"; "Liza"; "A.M. World"; "Muse Blues"; "Be Careful There's a Baby in th House"; "Unrequited to the Nth Degree"; "Lullabye"; "The You Hurt Me Mantra"; "The Man Who Couldn't Cry"; "Medley: I Know I'm Unhappy - Suicice Song". Digitized from the KPFT master reel
  - Doug Sahm and the Tex Mex Band live, 1974-08-15
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Papa Ain't Salty"; "Texas Tornados"; "Rain Rain"; "At the Crossroads"; "Stormy Monday"; "Georgia on My Mind"; "Wasted Days and Wasted Nights"; "San Antone (Is Anybody Going to). Performers: Doug Sahm - vocals, guitar, piano; Augie Meyer - organ and piano; Link Davis, Jr. - vocals, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano, organ; Doug Clifford - drums; Stu Cook - bass guitar. Originally played on KPFT Radio, later reboradcast by VPRO Radio, 1979-02-02
  - Townes Van Zandt live at Liberty Hall - KPFT (10.5" reel-to-reel audio), 1977-07 (Box 3)
    These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s.
  - Ryan Trimble video oral history, 2016-06-13
    These digitized video files consist of one master copy mp4 and one access copy located at scholarship.rice.edu.
  - Lynda Herrera video oral history, 2016-06-13
- Series IV: Scrapbook
  - Liberty Hall scrapbook, 1971-1972 (Box 2-3)
- Series V: Posters
  - Sub-Series A: Liberty Hall
    - The Dragon Lady's Revenge, San Franscisco Mime Troupe, 1971-11-13 - 1971-11-15 (Box 4)
    - The Flying Burrito Brothers, 1971-05-28 - 1971-05-29 (Box 4)
    - Big Mama Thorton, Lightning Hopkins (Reprint), 1971-05-12 - 1971-05-15 (Box 4)
    - B.W. Stevenson (2), 1973-03-01 - 1973-03-04 (Box 4)
    - Bonnie Raitt, Little Feat, 1973-03-22 - 1973-03-25 (Box 4)
    - Flash Cadillac, 1973-04-19 - 1973-04-22 (Box 4)
    - Pot Liquor and Commander Cody and His Lost Planet Airmen, 1973-04-26-1973-04-29 (Box 4)
    - Rory Gallagher, 1973-05-17-1973-05-18 (Box 4)
    - Mose Allison and Jimmy Rogers, 1973-06-14-1973-06-17 (Box 4)
    - John Paul Hammond, 1973-06-21-1973-06-24 (Box 4)
    - Robert Klein, 1973-07-05-1973-07-08 (Box 4)
    - Asleep at the Wheel, Willis Allan Ramsey, 1973-08-30 - 1973-09-02 (Box 4)
    - Jerry Jeff Walker, 1973-09-20-1973-09-23 (Box 4)
    - Don Sanders, Greezy Wheels, 1973-10-26-1973-10-28 (Box 4)
    - Michael Murphy, 1973-10-11 - 1973-10-15 (Box 4)
    - Benefit supporting Joe Villareal, 1973-10-17 (Box 4)
    - Clifton Chenier (2), 1973-10-31 (Box 4)
    - Little Feat, Joker Moon, 1973-11-01-1973-11-04 (Box 4)
    - Loudon Wainwright III, Franklin Ajaye, 1973-11-08 - 1973-11-11 (Box 4)
    - Mother Earth with Tracey Nelson, 1973-12-06-1973-12-09 (Box 4)
    - Jerry Jeff Walker, 1973-12-27-1973-12-31 (Box 4)
    - B.J. Thomas, 1974-02-01-1974-02-05 (Box 4)
    - B.W. Stevenson, 1974-02-14-1974-02-17 (Box 4)
    - David Bomberg (2), 1974-02-28 - 1974-03-03 (Box 4)
    - Bruce Springsteen (Copy), 1974-03-07 - 1974-03-10 (Box 4)
    - Navasota. The Nightcrawler (2), 1974-03-15-1974-03-16 (Box 4)
    - Goose Creek Symphony, The Old Lost Ramblers, 1974-03-28-1974-03-31 (Box 4)
    - Brewer & Shipley, The Ozark Mountain Dare Devils, 1974-04-07 (Box 4)
    - Doug Kershaw, 1974-04-11-1974-04-14 (Box 4)
    - Michael Murphy, Augie Meyers and the Western Music Co., 1974-04-25-1974-04-27 (Box 4)
    - Return Ron Waters to Austin featuring Lightnin' Hopkins, 1974-04-30 (Box 4)
    - Hoyt Axton, 1974-05-02 - 1974-05-05 (Box 4)
    - Sugar Cane Harris, 1974-05-09-1974-05-12 (Box 4)
    - Ace Trucking Co. (2), 1974-05-17-1974-05-19 (Box 4)
    - Ry Cooder, 1974-05-31-1974-06-01 (Box 4)
    - Michael Murphy, 1974-05-31-1974-06-03 (Box 4a)
    - Michael Murphy and Band Cosmo, Willis Allan Ramsey, 1974-06-06-1974-06-09 (Box 4a)
    - Jerry Jeff Walker, Augie Meyers and the Head Western Music Co., 1974-06-23-1974-06-24 (Box 4a)
    - Jimmy Buffett, 1974-06-27 - 1974-06-30 (Box 4a)
    - Doug Sahm and the Texas Tornadoes (2), 1974-08-15-1974-08-17 (Box 4a)
    - Rusty Weir, Sam Neely (2), 1974-08-22-1974-08-25 (Box 4a)
    - Willis Allan Ramsey, Professor Long Hair (3), 1974-09-19-1974-09-21 (Box 4a)
    - Navasota, The Lanier Greig Group (2), 1974-09-26-1974-09-28 (Box 4a)
    - Country Joe McDonald and The Old Stars, 1973-09-27-1973-09-30 (Box 4a)
    - B.W. Stevenson, Bob Jenkins, 1974-10-10-1974-10-12 (Box 4a)
    - Flash Cadillac and the Continental Kids, Dusty Drapes and the Dusters (2), 1974-10-19-1974-10-20 (Box 4a)
    - Freddie King, Fancy Space & the Rockin' Rhythm Daddies, 1974-10-24-1974-10-26 (Box 4a)
    - Clifton Chenier, Dave Davis, 1974-10-31 (Box 4a)
    - Brian Auger, 1974-11-14-1974-11-16 (Box 4a)
    - Freddie [Freddy] Fender, Greezy Wheels (3), 1974-12-05 - 1974-12-07 (Box 4a)
    - Goose Creek Symphony, Dusty Drapes and the Dusters (3 copies - 2 gradient, 1 white), 1974-12-12-1974-12-15 (Box 4a)
    - Billy Joel, Diana Marcovitz, 1974-12-19-1974-12-22 (Box 4a)
    - New Riders of the Purple Sage, B.W. Stevenson, Wheatfield, 1975-02-06-1975-02-09 (Box 4a)
    - Jonathan Edwards (2), 1975-02-28-1975-03-02 (Box 4a)
    - The Sir Douglas Quintet feat. Doug Sahm, Incognito, 1975-03-06-1975-03-09 (Box 4a)
    - Willis Allan Ramsey, Rick Casuals, 1975-03-20-1975-03-23 (Box 4a)
    - Loudon Wainwright, Murray McLaughlan, 1975-03-28-1975-03-29 (Box 4a)
    - Taj Mahal, Stoneground, 1975-04-22-1975-04-23 (Box 4a)
    - Proctor and Bergman of the Firesign Theater, Don Sanders (2 Copies), 1975-04-26-1975-04-27 (Box 4a)
    - B.W. Stevenson, Balcones Fault, 1975-05-08-1975-05-10 (Box 4a)
    - Ted Nugent and the Amboy Dukes, 1975-05-16-1975-05-17 (Box 4a)
    - Dr. John, 1975-05-22-1975-05-25 (Box 4a)
    - Tracey Nelson and Mother Earth, Greezy Wheels, 1975-06-12-1975-06-14 (Box 4b)
    - New Riders of the Purple Sage, Dixie Diesels (2 copies), 1975-06-20-1975-06-21 (Box 4b)
    - Pablo Cruise, 1975-07-24-1975-07-26 (Box 4a)
    - Goose Creek Symphony, Augie Meyers and the Western Head Band, 1975-07-31-1975-08-02 (Box 4b)
    - Tompall Glaser, 1975-08-07-1975-08-09 (Box 4b)
    - Tracey Nelson and The Mother Earth Band, Lightnin' Hopkins Blues Band (2), 1975-09-25-1975-09-27 (Box 4b)
    - Jimmie Spheeris and Tumbleweed Kid (2), 1975-10-09-1975-10-12 (Box 4b)
    - Willis Allan Ramsey, The Hello People, 1975-10-17-1975-10-19 (Box 4b)
    - Savoy Brown, 1975-10-24 (Box 4b)
    - Oz Knnoz (2), 1975-11-21-1975-11-22 (Box 4b)
    - Taj Mahal, Juke Boy Bonner, 1975-11-22-1975-11-23 (Box 4b)
    - Rory Gallagher, 1975-11-25-1975-11-26 (Box 4b)
    - Dog Tooth Violet, Wheatfield (2), 1975-11-28-1975-11-29 (Box 4b)
    - Jimmy Reed, Lightnin Hopkins, Luther Allison, 1975-12-04-1975-12-06 (Box 4b)
    - Jimmy Reed, Augie Meyers and the Western Head Band, Uncle Vinty, Vince Bell and Band, Don Sanders, 1975-12-30-1975-12-31 (Box 4b)
    - Clifton Chenier, Gatemouth Brown Revue (2), 1976-01-15-1976-01-17 (Box 4b)
    - David Bromberg, John Hiatt, 1976-01-29-1976-01-31 (Box 4b)
    - Balcones Fault, Dusty Drapes and the Dusters (2), 1976-02-19-1976-02-21 (Box 4b)
    - Loudon Wainwright, Bryan Bowers (2 copies - 1 missing top and bottom sections), 1976-03-12-1976-03-14 (Box 4b)
    - Maria Muldaur, 1976-04-15-1976-04-16 (Box 4b)
    - Freddie King, The Atlanta Rhythm Section (2 copies - 1 yellow, 1 gradient), 1976-04-23-1976-04-24 (Box 4b)
    - Roy Buchanan, 1976-05-13-1976-05-14 (Box 4b)
    - Saint Elmo's Fire, 1976-06-10-1976-06-12 (Box 4b)
    - Buddy Miles, 1976-06-17-1976-06-19 (Box 4b)
    - Tracey Nelson and Mother Earth, 1976-07-08-1976-07-10 (Box 4b)
    - The Liberty Hall Poster Show, ca. 2007 (Box 4b)
    - Practice Poster (2), n.d. (Box 4b)
    - Liberty Hall owners, employees, and musicians group photograph, 1976 (Map-drawer 196, Item 1)
      This is a blown up image with text and not an original photograph.
  - Sub-Series B: Showbar
    - Ponty Bone, 1989-02-16 - 1989-02-18 (Box 5)
    - The Tenth Annual Heartbreak Ball, 1989-02-14 (Box 5)
      Includes artists: Doctor Rockit, Jr. Medlow and the Bad Boys, Herschel Berry and the Natives, Tommie Lee Bradley, and Sean Walters.
    - Freddy Fender, 1989-02-23 - 1989-02-25 (Box 5)
    - Townes Van Zandt, 1990-03-03 (Box 5)
    - Uncle Tupelo (2), 1990-09-21 (Box 5)
    - Showbar, 1990s (Box 5)
    - Jerry Lightfoot, 03-09 - 03-11 (Box 5)
    - Robert Earl Keen (2), 07-14 (Box 5)
    - Trout Fishing in America, 10-27 - 10-28 (Box 5)
    - Trout Fishing in America (3), 12-22 (Box 5)